Never push a good man too far.
The Foreigner is a action, thriller, crime film directed by Martin Campbell.
Quan is a humble London businessman whose long-buried past erupts in a revenge-fueled vendetta when the only
person left for him to love – his teenage daughter – dies in an Irish Republican Army car bombing.
His relentless search to find the terrorists leads to a cat-and-mouse conflict with a British
government official whose own past may hold the clues to the identities of the elusive killers.
Liam Hennessy, played by Pierce Brosnan.
Quan Ngoc Minh, played by Jackie Chan.
Sean Morrison, played by Rory Fleck-Byrne.
Commander Richard Bromley, played by Ray Fearon.
Maggie / Sara McKay, played by Charlie Murphy.
Mary Hennessy, played by Orla Brady.
The Foreigner is a 2017 action thriller film directed by Martin Campbell from a screenplay
by David Marconi, based on the 1992 novel The Chinaman by Stephen Leather.
A British-Chinese-American co-production, starring Jackie Chan, Pierce Brosnan,
Michael McElhatton, Liu Tao, Charlie Murphy, Orla Brady, and Katie Leung.
The film follows a London-based Chinese Nùng restaurateur and
ex-soldier who seeks vengeance for the death of his daughter.
The Foreigner was released in China on 30 September 2017 by Wuzhou Film Distribution, in the United States on
13 October 2017 by STX Entertainment, and in the United Kingdom on 15 December 2017 on Netflix.
It received generally favorable reviews from critics with praise for its action sequences, musical
score, and against type performances of Chan and Brosnan, but criticized its formulaic plot.
The film grossed $145 million at the worldwide box office and was one of
2018's top ten most-watched Netflix original films in the UK.
The film explores themes of martial arts, london,
england, based on novel or book, bomb, revenge.
The tone is intense.